<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: entrepreneurship | Divisa C]]></title>
  <link href="http://misshula.github.com/blog/categories/entrepreneurship/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://misshula.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-12T12:58:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://misshula.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Misshula]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Months In - Am I An Entrepreneur Yet?]]></title>
    <link href="http://misshula.github.com/blog/2013/02/12/am-i-an-entrepreneur-yet/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T13:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://misshula.github.com/blog/2013/02/12/am-i-an-entrepreneur-yet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was young, I remember asking my dad  - “what is an Entrepreneur?” Quickly, he responded - “it’s someone without a job, son.”</p>

<p>Well, it’s been three months since ‘having a job’ and these are some of the things I’ve learned.</p>

<h3>You have a job</h3>


<p>Despite what other people want to tell you - you have work to do. You actually DO stuff. You often work a lot. I’d entertain the fact that my hours are more flexible, but just because I’m doing yoga on a Tuesday morning - doesn’t mean I’m not up till 2am on a Thursday - working.
I originally thought that I’d be working every hour of everyday, to ensure success for my company. But, that’s truly not the case. When things need to get done, I ensure that they do - but, taking a break and letting your brain relax is often the best thing for my productivity. It is extremely important that you don’t pretend to work when you are not. It is okay to not be working all the time - infact, I encourage it. Turns out, when you step away from work you often unconciously solve problems you have been wrestling with.</p>

<h3>You have a boss</h3>


<p>It’s you - and that person should be the toughest critic you’ve worked for. It’s not good enough to be just satisfied with something you create. You must be proud of what you do, and you shouldn’t stop until you are. But often, you can’t always be your biggest motivator. Set up goals with your teammates and take time for some constructive criticism along the way. Do things with a purpose and the rest will fall into place.</p>

<h3>You have to be creative</h3>


<p>You finally get to ‘put your money where your mouth is.’ You have to sharpen your skills and show what you’ve got. Too many times, I said ‘cool’ or ‘motivating’ things in interviews, or with people - but could always fall back on the fact I had a job to tie me up. Now, I have a passion that needs to be relayed in my words and represented in my actions. You don’t get handed the silver platter (or paper plate) very often - so make a meal fit for a king.</p>

<h3>You have to make real decisions</h3>


<p>Every decision you make is critical. This should not scare you, but encourage you even further. Every decision you make sculpts who you are and what your business is. When you own your own business - each decision means much more. Sculpt with a chisel and not a brush.</p>

<h3>You have to enjoy the ride</h3>


<p>Sure, there is some stress and a few road bumps along the way - but, it’s important to enjoy the ups and the downs. Yes, enjoy the downs. You learn from the downs and it helps balance the ups. If each day you learn something new, and every day is based on how wise you are - then, every day should get better. It can be a financial burden to start your own shop, but I often tell myself, “some people save for traveling, some people save for school, I saved for starting a business.” And I’m okay with it. We may not be buying yachts, but we are progressing each day, as business owners and more importantly - as people. I’m learning how the world works without the superficial, financial safety blanket that my generation grows up with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
